E. Adamson Hoebel Papers 1925-1983 Mss.Ms.Coll.43
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Subject files, 1927-1993; 4 boxes; 2.0 linear feet
  - Minnesota. Advisory Committee on Problems of Human Genetics, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Minnesota. Governor's Human Rights Commission, 1957, 1961 (Box 11)
  - New York University, 1929-1930, 1945 (Box 11)
  - Poem, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Putnam Letters, [1964] (Box 11)
  - Shoshone Indians' Legal Processes. Costs for the Study of, Jun.-Sep. 1934 (Box 11)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1953-1955, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations, 1955-1956, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Transcripts, 1927-1943 (Box 12)
    See also Oversized
  - United Press International, 1970 (Box 12)
  - United Pueblos Agency, 1933, 1946-1947, n.d. (Box 12)
  - United Pueblos Agency--Items, Misc. Dates; 6 folders (Box 12)
    - Folder 1 (Items 28-65) (Box 12)
    - Folder 2 (Items 66-103) (Box 12)
    - Folder 3 (Items 104-133) (Box 12)
    - Folder 4 (Items 134-170) (Box 12)
    - Folder 5 (Items 171-214) (Box 12)
    - Folder 6 (Items 215-267) (Box 12)
  - United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Folder 1, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1971-1973, n.d. (Box 13)
  - United States Public Health Service, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Universität Köln, 1928-1929 (Box 13)
  - University of Minnesota, 1955, 1961-1985, n.d. (Box 13)
  - University of Oxford, 1956 (Box 13)
  - University of Utah, 1948-1959, n.d. (Box 13)
  - War Relocation Authority, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Folder 1, 1942-1943 (Box 13)
    - Folder 2, 1944-1946, n.d. (Box 13)
  - World Law Project, 1950-1963, n.d. (Box 13)
    See also Ser.I, Landheer, B.
    See also Ser.I, McLaughlin, Mr. and Mrs. Robert C.
    See also Ser.I, Redfield, Robert
- Series VII. Photographs, 1928-1976?; 2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet
  Prints, slides, and one negative. Subjects and people depicted are often identified by Hoebel on the back of the photograph, and Hoebel himself appears in most of the pictures. Several of the photographs are attached to passports, which range in date from 1928 to 1975. One photograph shows Hoebel talking to two of his Shoshone informants. Native American Images Note: In 1933-1935, while studying the legal systems of the pre-literate, E. Adamson Hoebel took these photographs and slides of the Cheyenne, Comanche and Shoshone of Wyoming and Idaho, respectively. The fifteen black and white gelatin silver prints present native Cheyenne consultants and a brief look at the Comanche brush dance. Of note, twenty-six glass negative slides giving step-by-step detail of the Shoshone sun dance, including the sun-pole, the buffalo-head, and the grass offering. Other images in the collection include color slides of an undated trip to Mesa Verde National Park in Colorado that show cliff dwellings of the Pueblos. An oversize blueprint map includes Native American tribe settlements in Wyoming, Idaho, Utah and Nevada.
  - Anthropology Graduate Students Retirement Party, University of Minnesota, May 1972 (Box 26)
  - "Cheyenne Warriors. Sheridan, Wyoming", 1935 (Box 26)
    - Cheyenne men on horseback, 1935
  - [Comanche Brush Dance?], [1933?] (Box 26)
    - [Comanche Brush Dance?], 1933?
  - "Comanche Brush Dance. Ralph Linton Counting His WWI Coups at. Walters, Okla.", 1933 (Box 26)
    - Ralph Linton, 1933
  - Darland, Roy, E. Adamson Hoebel, and Regent Montague, 7 Jun 1968 (Box 26)
  - Engatura, Charlie (Box 26)
    See Ser.VII, Shoshone Field Work--Raphael Lavatta, Charlie Engatura, and E. Adamson Hoebel
  - Grand Canyon Expedition, 1968, 1969 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson, Jun. 1966 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson (Box 26)
    See also Ser.VII, Darland, Roy, E. Adamson Hoebel, and Regent Montague; See also Ser.VII, Shoshone Field Work--Raphael Lavatta, Charlie Engatura, and E. Adamson Hoebel
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson and Irene Hoebel, [1976?] (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson--Passport, 1928 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson--Passport, 1956 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson--Passport, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson--Passport, 1970 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson--Passport, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, Irene, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Hoebel, Irene (Box 26)
    -See also Ser.VII, Hoebel, E. Adamson and Irene Hoebel
  - Lavatta, Raphael (Box 26)
    -See Ser.VII, Shoshone Field Work--Raphael Lavatta, Charlie Engatura, and E. Adamson Hoebel
  - Linton, Ralph (Box 26)
    -See Ser.VII, "Comanche Brush Dance. Ralph Linton Counting His WWI Coups at. Walters, Okla."
  - [Man Standing on Top of Chimney] (Box 26)
  - Montague, Regent (Box 26)
    -See Ser.VII, Darland, Roy, E. Adamson Hoebel, and Regent Montague
  - "Memorial Service", 1944 (Box 26)
    -See also Ser.III, same title
  - Nicholson, Jed and Peter, Apr. 1972 (Box 26)
  - Shoshone Field Work--Raphael Lavatta, Charlie Engatura, and E. Adamson Hoebel, 1934 (Box 26)
  - "Shoshone Sun Dance", 1933 (Box 26)
  - "Shoshone Sun Dance", 1934 (Box 26)
    - Shoshone sun dance, 1934
  - Stonehenge, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Universität Köln--Negatives, [1928-1929] (Box 26)
  - War Relocation Authority, n.d. (Box 26)
  - "Zia Snake Society Pot", n.d. (Box 26)
    - Zia Pueblo pottery, n.d.
  - "Sun Dance", [193-?] (Box Slides)
  - "Mesa Verde", n.d. (Box Slides)
  - "New Mexico Field Trip"; "Arches & Bridges Trip", n.d. (Box Slides)
  - "River Trip", n.d. (Box Slides)
  - "Bryce & Capital Reef", n.d. (Box Slides)
- Series III. Works by Hoebel, 1927-1987; 4 boxes; 2 linear feet
  Handwritten and typed notes, outlines, and drafts of lectures, articles, books, and reviews; in some instances published works are also included. This series is arranged alphabetically by title. For each work, the notes, drafts, and published versions are filed together. The series contains several papers Hoebel wrote as a student, including his thesis and dissertation; the oldest item in the series is a paper written in 1927 for an introductory course in economics. Manuscript versions of A Cheyenne Sketchbook and The Cheyennes: Indians of the Great Plains are included in this series, as well as unpublished legal codes written for the use of the Kerasan Pueblo Indians. A file with bibliographic information is included in this series.
  - The American Behavioral Scientist--Preface, Nov. 1981 (Box 14)
  - "American Culture in Perspective", n.d. (Box 14)
  - "The American Federation of Labor in Its Recent Relations to the International Federation of Trade Unions", 1927 (Box 14)
  - American Social and Cultural Anthropology--Review (Box 14)
  - "American World View", n.d. (Box 14)
  - "Ancient Times", n.d. (Box 14)
  - An Anthropologist at Work: Writings of Ruth Benedict by Margaret Mead--Review, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Anthropology and Early Law edited by Lawrence Krader--Review, [1968] (Box 14)
  - "Anthropology, Law, and Genetic Inheritance" (Box 14)
  - Arapahoe Politics, 1851-1978: Symbols in Crises of Authority by Loretta Fowler--Review, 1984 (Box 15)
  - "Authority in Primitive Societies", [1958] (Box 15)
  - "Autobiographical Statement", n.d. (Box 15)
  - "B. Malinowski and Radcliffe Brown", 1931 (Box 15)
  - Barnum, Cyrus--Memorial, n.d. (Box 15)
  - "Beziehungslehre--L. von Wiese", 1930 (Box 15)
  - [Birth]--Lecture, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Brewster, Kingman, Jr.--Introduction at Inauguration of President Malcolm Moss at University of Minnesota, 9 May 1968 (Box 15)
  - Centennial Lecture--University of Utah, 1950? (Box 15)
  - "Cheyenne Killing", n.d. (Box 15)
  - Cheyenne Memories by John Stands in Timber and Margot Liberty and Howling Wolf: A Cheyenne Warrior's Graphic Interpretation of His People by Karen Daniels Petersen--Review, [1969] (Box 15)
  - A Cheyenne Sketchbook--with Karen Daniels Petersen, [1964]; 2 folders (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.I, University of Oklahoma Press
  - The Cheyennes: Indians of the Great Plains, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - "Christmas: Its Origin and Some Connected Practices"--Lecture (Box 15)
    See also Ser.VII, Stonehenge
  - "Comanche", n.d. (Box 15)
  - Comanche Days by Albert S. Giles, Sr.--Review, [1974] (Box 15)
  - The Comanches, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Commencement Address, n.d. (Box 16)
  - "Comparative Greetings"--Lecture, n.d. (Box 16)
  - "Comparative Systems of Law"--Lecture, Jan. 1945 (Box 16)
    -See also Ser.III, "The Function of Law"
  - "The Contribution of Professor Raymond Kennedy to Indonesian Ethnology"--Proofs, [1944] (Box 16)
  - Culture in History: Essays in Honor of Paul Radin edited by Stanley Diamond--Review, 3 Nov. 1961 (Box 16)
  - "The Cultures and Evolution of the Indians", 18 Jul. 1969 (Box 16)
  - "Custom Law", n.d. (Box 16)
  - "'Customary Law' in African Courts and Legislatures" (Box 16)
  - "The Democratic Spirit", 27 Aug. 1954 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.VI, Law and Social Relations--Seminar, Lehigh University
  - A Diary in the Strict Sense of the Term by Bronislav Malinowski--Review, 1967 (Box 16)
  - The Discourse of Law edited by Sally Humphreys--Review, [1985] (Box 16)
  - "Due Process"--Lecture at University of Kansas Law School, 1965 (Box 16)
  - [Dying and Revival Experiences]--Fragment of Ms. (Box 16)
  - "Early Fieldwork in the Plains"--Lecture, 6 Nov. 1987 (Box 16)
  - "The Embattled Judiciary", 1970 (Box 16)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica--Articles, 1958-1974 (Box 16)
  - "Energy and the Evolution of Culture"--Lecture (Box 16)
  - "Evaluation of Evidence"--Lecture for Freshman English, n.d. (Box 16)
  - "The Family: More Time to Devote to Exploring Life", 28 May 1967 (Box 16)
  - "The Function of Law"--Lecture, Dec. 1944 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.III, "Comparative Systems of Law"
  - "Fundamental Cultural Postulates and "the Meaning of Life'", Mar. 1969 (Box 16)
  - "Fundamental Cultural Postulates Revisited"--Lecture (Box 16)
  - Fundamental Principles of the Sociology of Law by E. Ehrlich--Notes (Box 16)
  - Grenville Goodwin among the Western Apache: Letters from the Field edited by Morris E. Opler--Review, [197-] (Box 16)
  - Guide to American Law--Articles, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Hear Me, My Chiefs! by Herbert Ravenel Sass--Review, Apr. 1941 (Box 16)
  - "Home Conditions and Delinquency among Adolescent Boys", 18 Jun. 1930 (Box 16)
  - "How Advanced Is Our Legal System?: A Look by a Primitive Lawyer", 13 Oct. 1970 (Box 16)
  - The Indians of Texas: From Prehistoric to Modern Times by W.W. Newcomb, Jr.--Review, [1963] (Box 16)
  - "Karl Llewellyn: Anthropological Jurisprude", 1964 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.VI, Legal Anthropology--The University of Arizona
  - Ishi the Last Yahi: A Documentary History edited by Robert F. Heizer and Theodora Kroeber--Review, [1979] (Box 16)
  - "Islamic Law"--Lecture, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Justice and Judgment among the Tiv by Paul Bohannon--Review, 1958 (Box 16)
  - "Karl Llewellyn: Anthropological Jurisprude", 1964 (Box 16)
  - "Keresan Pueblo Law", 1966 (Box 16)
  - The Kiowas by M.P. Marshall--Review, [1962] (Box 16)
  - The Last Frontier by Howard Fast--Review, Jan. 1942 (Box 16)
  - "Law and Anthropology", 1946 (Box 16)
  - Law as Process: An Anthropological Approach by Sally Falk Moore--Review, 1978 (Box 16)
  - "Law, Culture and Society" (Box 16)
  - The Law of Primitive Man--Preface to the Japanese Translation, 15 Dec. 1983 (Box 16)
  - "A Map of the World's Law" by J.H. Wigmore--Notes, n.d. (Box 16)
  - "Margaret Mead, Derek Freeman--Two Samoas", 1983 (Box 16)
  - "Mathilda Cox Stevenson and the Chinese Lions of Zia" (Box 16)
  - "Memorial Service", 5 Aug. 1944 (Box 16)
    See also Ser.I, War Relocation Authority, Hoebel to Rudolf Kagey, 2 Aug. 1944
  - Metal Weapons, Tools, and Ornaments of the Teton Dakota Indians by James Austin Hanson--Review (Box 16)
  - "National Law, Legal Pluralism, and Civil Liberties"--Lecture, [May 1970] (Box 16)
    See also Ser.I, Rijksuniversiteit Te Leiden
  - Native Californians: A Theoretical Retrospective edited by Lowell J. Bean and Thomas C. Blackburn--Review, [1976] (Box 16)
  - "The Nature of Law in the Light of Anthropology", ca. 1936 (Box 16)
  - The New International 1959 Yearbook: Events of 1958--Article on Anthropology, 1969 (Box 16)
  - "O. Meredith Wilson"--Speech at Library Dedication, 13 May 1969 (Box 17)
  - "On Cheyenne Sociopolitical Organization", n.d. (Box 17)
  - "On Going Out into the World - Nineteen Sixty-Eight!"--Commencement Address at University of Minnesota, 7 Jun. 1968 (Box 17)
  - "On the Methodology of Anthropology", n.d. (Box 17)
  - One Hundred Years of Anthropology edited by J.O. Brew--Review, [1971] (Box 17)
  - [Piegan Photographs] by Roland Reed--Review (Box 17)
  - Plains Indian Painting: A Description of an Aboriginal American Art by John Canfield Ewers--Review, Oct. 1939 (Box 17)
  - The Plains Indians: A Critical Bibliography, 1977 (Box 17)
  - "The Political Organization and Law-Ways of the Comanche Indians", [1934] (Box 17)
  - "Primitive Law", n.d. (Box 17)
  - "Primitive Law among the American Indians"--Centennial Lecture at University of Utah, 1951 (Box 17)
  - Primitive Law Past and Present by A.S. Diamond--Review, [197-] (Box 17)
  - "Principles in Anthropology", [1961] (Box 17)
  - "Program on Contemporary Islam in Non-Arabic Countries: Pakistan Research Project", n.d. (Box 17)
  - "Progress - A Long Range View"--Lecture, 28 Mar. 1956 (Box 17)
  - "Proposal for a Conference on the Foundations of Major Legal Systems", [1952?] (Box 17)
  - The Quest for Law by William Seagle--Review, 1942 (Box 17)
  - The Rites of Passage by Arnold van Gennep--Review, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Senate Committee on Foreign Relations. Subcommittee on Disarmament--Statement, 16 Jun. 1956 (Box 17)
  - "Social Control in an African Society." [Review of] A Study of the Arusha: Agricultural Masai of Northern Tanganyika by P.H. Gulliver, [1963] (Box 17)
  - "Social Integration: Analysis of the Lectures of Professor Radcliffe-Brown, 1931 (Box 17)
  - Sweet Medicine: The Continuing Role of the Sacred Arrows, the Sun Dance, and the Sacred Buffalo Hat in Northern Cheyenne History by Peter J. Powell--Review, [1971] (Box 17)
  - "Theory and Practice in the Codification of Primitive "Common Law""--Lecture, 1955 (Box 17)
  - "Three Studies in African Law", [1961] (Box 17)
  - "A Tribute to President Wilson", May 1967 (Box 17)
  - "Two Samoas: Margaret Mead and Derek Freeman" (Box 17)
    See Ser.III, "Margaret Mead, Derek Freeman--Two Samoas"
  - The Ultimate Sanction: A Cross-Cultural Study of Capital Punishment by Keith Otterbein--Review, n.d. (Box 17)
  - United States-Comanche Relations: The Reservation Years by William T. Hagan--Review, [1976] (Box 17)
  - "What Do Anthropologists Do?"--Lecture, n.d. (Box 17)
  - The World Book Encyclopedia--Articles, [1958] (Box 17)
  - Zia, n.d. (Box 17)
- Series IV. Works by others, 1934-1991; 2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet
  Papers written by students of Hoebel for courses that he taught, as well as articles and papers written by colleagues such as Max Gluckman. O. Meredith Wilson's lecture about Hoebel's contribution to anthropology is in this series. Also included is a review written by Pierre Bettez Gravel of Hoebel's book, Anthropology: The Study of Man, and Hoebel's response to the review. This series is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title.
  - "The Teton Sioux", 20 Jan. 1969; Agard, Lucia (Box 18)
  - "A Pig in the Hand Is Worth Two in the Bush", 1964; Allen, Sharon (Box 18)
  - Man in the Primitive World by E. Adamson Hoebel--Review, 1 Nov. 1958; Alpenfels, Ethel J. (Box 18)
  - "Handbook for Field Studies in the Anthropology of Law", 14 Jun. 1968; Aschenbrenner, Stan E. (Box 18)
  - "Living Philosophies, II: An Anthropologist's Credo", 27 Aug. 1938; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 18)
  - "A Deep Look at America--1970", 12 Oct. 1970; Brogan, Denis (Box 18)
  - "New World Pastoralism: A Study of the Comanche Indians", 1986; Canty, Carol Shannon (Box 18)
  - "L'Antropologia Giuridica di E. Adamson Hoebel", [1987]; De Micheli Consonni, Cristina (Box 19)
    In Italian
  - "Bibliographie des Oeuvres de E.A. Hoebel", 1988; De Micheli Consonni, Cristina (Box 19)
  - "Shoshone Kinship Structures and Their Significance for Anthropological Theory", 1980; Eggan, Fred, 1906-1991 (Box 19)
  - "Fa'apua'a Fa'am_ and Margaret Mead", Dec. 1989; Freeman, Derek (Box 19)
  - "A Memorandum on the Historical Scholarship and Editorial Practices of Professor Adam Kuper", 20 Dec. 1991; Freeman, Derek (Box 19)
  - The Comanches: Lords of the South Plains by Ernest Wallace and E. Adamson Hoebel--Review, 1986; Gelo, Daniel J. (Box 19)
  - "Role of the Bargtse King in the Judicial Process", [1961]; Gluckman, Max, 1911-1975 (Box 19)
  - "Spouse, Child, Parent or Sibling? - Who Should Be Saved? (The Disputed Passage in Sophocles's Antigone)", [1978]; Gluckman, Max, 1911-1975 (Box 19)
  - Anthropology: The Study of Man by E. Adamson Hoebel--Review, [1966]; Gravel, Pierre Bettez (Box 19)
    Includes Hoebel's response
  - "Religious Practice in Islamic Law", n.d.; Hiebert, Paul Gordon (Box 19)
  - Behavioral Science Research and Arms Control", May 1970; Janowitz, Morris (Box 19)
  - "Peyote Questionnaire", [193-?]; La Barre, Weston (Box 19)
  - Unidentified, n.d.; Liberty, Margot (Box 19)
  - "Primitive Culture"--Presentation to the Anthropology Seminar at Columbia University, 1934; Llewellyn, Karl N. (Box 19)
  - "Southern Cheyenne", n.d.; Moore, John (Box 19)
  - "Beyond War and Peace: Hoebel's Postulational Approach and Multi-Ethnic Reality", 1988; Nicholson, Maggi E.R. (Box 19)
  - -See also Ser.IV, Rohrl, Vivian J., M.E.R. Nicholson, and Mario D. Zamora, "The Anthropology of Peace in Honor of Professor E. Adamson Hoebel"--Introduction, Nicholson, Maggi E.R. (Box 19)
  - "The Anthropology of Peace in Honor of Professor E. Adamson Hoebel"--Introduction, [198-]; Rohrl, Vivian J., M.E.R. Nicholson, and Mario D. Zamora (Box 19)
  - "The Plains Culture Area Concept: A Critical Review", 1976; Scaglion, Richard (Box 19)
  - "The Indians and Modern Society", 1949; Smith, Marian W. (Box 19)
  - "Will the Real Cheyenne Please Stand Up"--Lecture, 23 May 1972; Wilson, Owen Meredith (Box 19)
  - Zamora, Mario D. (Box 19)
    -See Ser.IV, Rohrl, Vivian J., M.E.R. Nicholson, and Mario D. Zamora, "The Anthropology of Peace in Honor of Professor E. Adamson Hoebel"--Introduction
- Series V. Research notes, 1932-1950; 9 boxes; 4.75 linear feet
  Notes on the subjects of the Mandans; Pueblos; Sioux; and the "General Phonetic Scheme." There are also notes on interviews with Zia Pueblos; Shoshone tales, including Coyote Tales; and notes and collected materials on the Plains Indians. Also in this series are seven card files: "Comanche Field Notes"; "Ethnographic Notes From Library Sources" (2 boxes); "Hopi Notes"; "Northern Cheyenne Field Notes"; "Northern Shoshone Notes, Seedeater Shoshone Folktales, and Unidentified Notes"; and "Pueblo Notes."
  - Comanche Field Notes, 1933 (Box 20)
  - "Comparative Data. Shoshone - Comanche Kin Terms", n.d. (Box 20)
  - Ethnographic Notes From Library Sources 2 Folders, 1932-1948 (Box 20)
  - "The General Phonetic Scheme", n.d. (Box 20)
  - Mandan (Box 20)
  - Northern Cheyenne Field Notes, 1935-1936 (Box 20)
  - Northern Shoshone Notes; Seedeater Shoshone Folktales; Unidentified Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 20)
  - Plains Indians (Box 20)
  - Pueblo Notes, 1944-1950 (Box 20)
  - Pueblos, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Shoshone Tales, 1934; 2 Folders (Box 21)
  - Sioux, n.d. (Box 21)
  - "Zia Pueblo", 1930s-1940s (Box 21)
  - Comanche Field Notes, 1933 (Box 23 (card file 1))
  - Ethnographic Notes From Library (Sources #1), 1932-1948 (Box 23 (card file 2))
  - Ethnographic Notes From Library (Sources #2), 1932-1948 (Box 23 (card file 3))
  - Hopi Notes, 1933 (Box 23 (card file 4))
  - Northern Cheyenne Field Notes, 1935-1936 (Box 23 (card file 5))
  - Northern Shoshone Notes; Seedeater Shoshone Folktales; Unidentified Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 23 (card file 6))
  - Pueblo Notes, 1944-1950 (Box 23 (card file 7))
- Series VI. Course materials, 1930s-1980; 2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet
  Course notes and outlines for lectures that Hoebel gave for anthropology courses at the University of Minnesota in the 1960s and 1970s; a legal anthropology course at the University of Arizona, 1974-1975; and an anthropology and law seminar at Lehigh University in 1980. Also included in this series are notes that Hoebel took as a student at Columbia University in the classes of Franz Boas and Ruth Benedict, among others.
  - Anthropology 207B, Jan. 1941 (Box 24)
  - Columbia University--Course Notes, [193-]; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Cultural Anthropology--Anthropology 222, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Indians of the Great Plains--Anthropology 115 (Box 24)
  - Indians of the Great Plains--Anthropology 5-212, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box 24)
  - "Last Class", 5 Jun. 1972 (Box 24)
  - Law and Anthropology--Anthropology 160, 1960, 1966, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Law and Social Relations--Seminar, Lehigh University, 1980 (Box 24)
    See also Ser.III, "The Democratic Spirit"; See also Ser.III, "The Embattled Judiciary"
  - Law-ways of Primitive Man--Anthropology 172, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Legal Anthropology--The University of Arizona, 1974-1975 (Box 24)
  - Personality and Culture--Anthropology 165, 1960-1961, n.d. (Box 24)
  - The Plains Indians--Lehigh University (Box 24)
  - Plains Indians of North America--Anthropology 182 (Box 24)
  - Religious Dogma in Islamic Law, 1958 (Box 25)
  - "Values"--Seminar at University of Minnesota, 1954 (Box 25)